我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
我年幼时  看到自己的母亲
When I was a child, I saw my mother
被令人难以置信的东西杀害
killed by something impossible.
巴里  快跑
Run, Barry, run!
我父亲因为谋杀母亲进了监狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist
但我秘密地用自己的速度打击犯罪
but secretly, I use my speed to fight crime
寻找跟我一样的人
and find others like me.
终有一天  我会找到杀害母亲的凶手
And one day, I'll find who killed my mother
-妈妈  -让我父亲沉冤得雪
- Mom. - And get justice for my father.
我就是  闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on The Flash...
那是巴里以前的家
That's Barry's old house.
也许时隔太久  一切都不一样了
Maybe it's been too long. Everything's different.
除了那面镜子
Except that mirror.
这面镜子可能含有
This mirror might contain photographs
那晚发生的情景的照片
of what happened that night.
那血迹属于那晚出现在这里的
That blood belongs to one of the two speedsters
其中一个极速者
that was here that night.
那是巴里的血  成年的巴里
It's Barry's... as an adult.
斯泰因夫人  你见过这个人吗
Mrs. Stein, have you seen this person?
-见过  -他甚至不再是罗尼了
- Yes. - He's not even Ronnie anymore.
他是占据罗尼身体的马丁·斯泰因
He's Martin Stein walking around in Ronnie's body.
任何尝试分离他们俩的行为
Any attempt we make to separate the two of them
都有可能造成灾难性的核爆炸
could be catastrophic and nuclear explosion.
巴里
Barry?
巴里  你那里发生什么了
Barry, what happened out there?
你们没事吧
Are you guys okay?
-你还好吗  -我想是吧
- Are you okay? - I think so.
没事
I think so.
天呐  核爆炸
Oh, God. The nuclear explosion.
很难说我们究竟接触到了多少核辐射
There's no telling how much radiation we were exposed to.
等一下  等等  这不可能
Wait--wait, wait, wait, wait, this can't be.
衣服里的盖革计数器
The Geiger counter in the suit--
上面的读数小于一毫拉德
it's reading less than one millirad.
但那是正常值啊
But that's normal.
没有产生核辐射
There's no radiation.
我们走
Let's go.
成功了吗
Did it work?
你分开他们了吗
Did you separate them?
我不知道
I don't know.
罗尼
Ronnie?
告诉我你叫什么
Tell me your name.
罗尼·雷蒙德
Ronnie Raymond.
凯特
Cait.
是我
It's me.
不好意思
Pardon me.
很显然我需要换一下衣服
Obviously, I need a change of clothes.
很高兴再次见到你本人  斯泰因教授
Nice to see you in the flesh again, Professor Stein.
我们要回家了
We're coming home.
我们所有人
All of us.
-罗尼·雷蒙德  -西斯科
- Ronnie Raymond. - Cisco.
老兄
Man.
我想死你了
I missed you so much, man.
我不应该把你锁在里面的
I shouldn't have locked you in there.
别说了
Hey... don't.
欢迎回来  雷蒙德先生
Welcome back, Mr. Raymond.
威尔斯博士
Dr. Wells.
凯特琳把你的遭遇告诉我了
Caitlin told me what happened to you.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
我坐上轮椅都怪自己
I'm responsible for putting myself in this chair.
而我现在还活着是多亏了你  谢谢你
You are responsible for my still being alive-- thank you.
你说过你会带他回来  你也做到了
You said you'd bring him back, and you did.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
打扰一下
Excuse me?
我们接下来要准备唱圣歌了吗
Are we all planning to sing Kumbaya next?
我想你就是斯泰因教授
Professor Stein, I presume.
哈里森·威尔斯
Harrison Wells.
有什么地方可以让我梳洗一下
Do you have somewhere I can freshen up
换换衣服吗
and get a change of clothes?
当然有
Of course.
这边请  教授
Right this way, Professor.
将军  你看到这个了吗
General, are you getting this?
看到了  中士
Roger that, Sergeant.
长官  请看这里
Sir, look at this.
两种压痕的脚印
Two imprints of impact.
两种脚印
Two imprints.
两个不同的人
Two different people.
是火风暴  他被分离了
It's Firestorm. He's separated.
你的生命体征看上去都很正常
Your vitals appear to be normal,
除了你有38.1度的轻烧
except you have a slight fever of 100.6.
凯特  我没事  我保证
Cait, I'm fine, I promise.
我知道  但是我们必须...
I know, but we just need to be...
我都忘了撞见你们俩
Yep-- just when I forgot how awkward it was
会有多尴尬了
to walk in on you two.
你很快就会再次习惯的
Well, you can get used to it again.
我为教授做了全面的医学检查
So I did a full medical workup on the professor.
结果表明  因为他和罗尼分开了
It turns out that now that he and Ronnie are separated,
他们不再具有
they no longer possess the ability
控制核能量的超能力
to harness nuclear energy.
斯泰因教授  看上去
Professor Stein, you seem to be running
你也有一点发烧
a little hot as well.
和罗尼一样  38度
Same as Ronnie-- 100.6.
连汗都没怎么出  斯诺博士
Hardly a sweat, Dr. Snow.
但愿我和罗纳德唯一的共同点就是--
And hopefully now the only thing Ronald and I have in common--
是罗尼
It's Ronnie.
你会怀念能飞的日子吗
You gonna miss being able to fly?
如果我是控制飞行的那方就好了
Yeah, maybe if I was the one holding the controller.
这是什么意思
Meaning?
你不是最负责的搭档
Meaning, you weren't the most conscientious body-mate.
你觉得我让你活着
So you do not consider keeping you alive
还不算负责
to be conscientious?
活着吗
Alive?
我们住在桥洞里  吃的都是垃圾
We were living under a bridge, eating garbage.
让我变为支配方
I did not determine that it would be my mind
可不是我的主意
that would dominate our existence,
不过谢天谢地掌控身体的是我
but thank God it was.
我随时可以感受到你的恐惧和惊慌
I could feel your fear and panic,
当时这种情感完全可以
emotions that likely would have gotten us killed
毁掉我们
in that state.
你一直压抑着我
You kept me buried down.
你不让我接近她
You kept me from her.
正因为这样  她现在还活着
Which is likely why she's still alive.
现在看来  我们在一起的时间
Now I believe you and I have spent
已经够多了
quite enough time together.
是啊
Yeah.
我想回家见我妻子
I would like to go home to see my wife.
-艾伦先生会带你回去  -谢谢
- Mr. Allen will take you. - Thank you.
-我想吃披萨  -这就去给你买
- I need some pizza. - You got it.
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
等等
Oh, wait.
我该说什么好
What should I say?
我觉得你什么都不需要说
I don't think you're gonna have to say anything.
克莱丽莎
Clarissa.
让你经受这一切真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry I put you through this.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这位先生  巴里
Mister... Barry.
怎么了
Yeah?
巴里  我知道自己挺不客气的
Barry, I--I know I can be difficult,
但谢谢你带我回家
but thank you for bringing me home.
后会有期  教授
I'll see you soon, Professor.
我给你留了三条言
I left you three messages.
我看到了  抱歉
Yeah, I know. I'm sorry.
抱歉是指不回我留言
About the lack of communication,
还是指巴德兰斯被炸出一个洞
or that new hole out in the Badlands?
我们都没出事  谢谢关心
We're all fine, thanks.
我找你不是为了爆炸的事
I wasn't calling about the explosion.
有东西要给你看
I have to show you something.
什么
What?
这房子比我记忆中的要小
It's smaller than I remember.
是啊
Yeah.
那是因为你长大了
It's because you're bigger.
你有来过吗
Have you been in here?
-我是说最近  -没有
- I mean, recently. - No.
自从那晚后  我就再没有来过
I haven't been in this house since that night.
巴仔  你还记得这面镜子吗
Bar? This mirror, you remember it?
记得  那是我祖母的镜子
Yeah. It belonged to my grandma.
怎么还在这里
How is it still here?
它还在是好事
Just be glad it is.
我不知道西斯科是怎么做的  不过
Look...I don't fully know how Cisco did it, but...
做什么  乔  我们在这做什么
Did what? Joe, what are we doing here?
妈妈
Mom.
可以很清楚地看见
You can definitely see two very fast people
两个极速者在你妈妈周围打斗
fighting around your mother.
两个极速者
Two speedsters.
你看见了吗
You see that?
那抹血迹
The blood?
西斯科和我检测了里面的DNA
Cisco and I had the DNA tested.
是你的血
It's yours.
不可能
No, it's not. That's impossible.
我当时都还没下楼
I wasn't even downstairs yet.
不  巴里  不是幼时的你
No, Barry. Not that you.
是现在的你
This you.
西斯科检测了样本  里面的蛋白质
Cisco had the samples analyzed and the proteins
表明血迹是属于成年人的  不是小孩的
in the blood were that of an adult, not a child.
这样的话
But that means--
第二个极速者  试图打败
The second speedster, the one trying to stop
黄衣人的那个
the man in yellow--
是闪电侠
is The Flash.
是我
That's me.
闪电侠
第一季第十四集
时间旅行
Time travel.
要说过去五个月都证明了什么
If the last five months have proven anything,
那就是世间无奇不有
it's that anything can exist,
但真要说到时间旅行
but to actually travel through time?
历史上最聪明的人们
Well, the greatest minds in human history
集中了所有的智慧来解开这个谜题
put their collective genius towards solving that puzzle.
所以有没有可能
So. Is it possible?
有可能
Yes, it's possible.
但还不确定
But problematic.
假设你能创造出足够的条件
Assuming you could create the conditions necessary
来完成时间旅行  这趟旅行
to take that journey, well, that journey would then be
会充满未知的陷阱
fraught with potential pitfalls.
比如说诺维科夫自洽性原则
The Novikov Principle of Self-consistency, for example.
那是什么
Wait, the what, now?
如果你回到过去改变了某事
If you travel back in time to change something,
这种改动就会从因果上改变这件事
then you end up being the causal factor of that event.
就像《终结者》电影一样
Like Terminator.
或者说时间有弹性吗
Or is time plastic?
时间是否易变  以至于时间线的改动
Is it mutable whereby any changes to the continuum
能创造出新的时间线
could create an alternate timeline.
《回到未来》
Back To The Future.
这个我也看过了
Saw that one too.
布朗博士  电影很不错
Doc Brown. Tremendous picture.
所以答案是什么
Right. So what's the answer?
我算得上是个聪明的人  不过乔
I might be a clever guy, Joe,
但如果你想让我
but if you're asking me
给你一个可行的时间旅行理论
to give you a working theory on how to travel through time,
我还做不到
I'm afraid I just can't do that.
你可以跟别人谈谈这事
There is someone else you can talk to about this.
酥皮卷
Danish?
你为什么会有尖端科研实验室
Why do you have a blueprint of the S.T.A.R. Labs
粒子加速器的蓝图
particle accelerator?
你还懂物理吗
Do you actually know anything about physics?
什么都不懂  就像多斯拉其语一样
Not a thing. Might as well be in Dothraki.
多斯拉其语  《冰与火之歌》中作者自创的语言
所以尖端科研实验室还有其它的秘密
So what more is there with the S.T.A.R. Labs story?
唯一的新线索就是
The only new piece of information
哈里森·威尔斯承认
is the fact that Harrison Wells admitted
他曾被警告过会出事
that he was warned of a potential disaster.
是的  你觉得他为什么要那么做
Yeah. Why do you think he did that?
因为他是个好人吗
Because he's a good person?
-他是吗  -是的
- Is he? - Yes.
他救了我朋友的命
He saved my friend's life.
他那晚被闪电击中了
He was struck by lightning that night
威尔斯博士和他的人救了他
and Dr. Wells and his team kept him alive.
然后呢
So?
如果不是因为威尔斯
Your friend wouldn't have needed saving
你的朋友也不需要被救了
if Wells hadn't zapped him in the first place.
那是个意外
It was an accident.
如果不是呢
What if it wasn't?
这么说你认为哈里森·威尔斯
So you think Harrison Wells
是故意让粒子加速器爆炸的
wanted the particle accelerator to explode?
他为什么要那么做
Why would he do that?
我不知道那座楼里发生了什么
I don't know what goes on inside that building.
但我觉得你认识知情的人
But I think you know some people who do.
你给了我块酥皮卷
So you think I would investigate my friends
我就要去帮你调查我的朋友们吗
because you got me a danish?
我觉得你去调查  是因为你真的想知道
I think that you'll do it because you really want
那座楼里发生了什么
to know what goes on inside that building.
巴里
Barry?
斯泰因夫人  很抱歉打扰你
Mrs. Stein, I'm sorry to bother you here,
斯泰因教授在吗
but is Professor Stein here right now?
我们分开了一年
Well, after a year apart,
我绝不会让他离开我的视线
I'm not letting him out of my sight.
尖端科研实验室给马丁做了一些测试
S.T.A.R. labs did quite a few tests on Martin,
对吧  他们认为他没事吗
didn't they? And they said he was fine?
是的  怎么了  有什么问题吗
Yeah. Why, is something wrong?
他只是有点  跟以前不一样了
He just seems a little different, is all.
怎么个不一样法
Different how?
他一直在要披萨吃  马丁以前很讨厌披萨的
He's been asking for pizza. Martin despises pizza.
是送披萨的吗  艾伦先生
Is that the delivery man? Oh, Mr. Allen.
我希望你不介意兼职做一次送披萨的吧
I suppose it's too much to hope you moonlight as a pizza boy.
我快饿死了
I am famished.
没问题
Okay.
太厉害了  请进来吧
Bravo! Please, come in.
艾伦先生
Mr. Allen.
需要我帮什么
What can I do for you?
我想跟你谈一下
I-- I needed to talk to you about a paper
你25年前为牛津大学出版社
that you wrote 25 years ago
写过的一篇论文
for the Oxford University Press.
我给那家出版社写过很多论文
I've written many papers for that publication.
能不能具体说一下论文的内容
Could you be more specific about the subject matter?
时间旅行
Time travel.
这是我当时关于那个问题
These are just a few of the random thoughts
几个随意的看法
I've had on the subject.
几个
Few?
你看  我认为时空
See, I believe that space-time
是一条流畅的大道
is a free-flowing highway
与物理世界相交互
that intersects the physical world.
我们当下的时间位于道路入口和出口之间
We live in--in the moments between the on and off ramps.
理论上  要想穿越时间
Theoretically, to travel through time,
只需要找到办法在大道上行进即可
one merely needs to find a way onto the highway.
你是认为实际上是有可能
Okay, so--so you're saying that this is actually possible
穿越到未来的吗
to--to travel into the future?
肯定可以
Undoubtedly.
那回到过去呢
What about the past?
也可以
Yes.
我一定会选择回到
My own personal choice would be
1893年的芝加哥世界博览会
the Chicago World's Fair, 1893.
我想尼古拉·特斯拉和我肯定会
I--I think Nicola Tesla and I would have
进行一场精彩的辩论
some wonderful arguments.
那你呢
What about you?
你对回到过去有兴趣吗
Would you be interested in taking a trip into history?
我想我已经回过了
I think that I already have.
教授...
Professor...
十五年前  我妈妈被谋杀了
15 years ago, my mom was murdered
而最近我们发现的证据表明...
and we recently discovered some evidence that...
那晚我在场  但不是以孩子身份
I was there that night, and not just as a kid,
而是成人
but as an adult.
肯定是你那惊人的速度产生的副作用
That must be a side effect of your incredible speed.
在未来的某一天
In some future date,
你移动的非常之快
you actually move so fast
以至于积攒了大量动能
that the resulting kinetic energy buildup
在时空连续统上穿了一个洞
smashes a hole in the space-time continuum!
你似乎对这可能性很失望
You seem disappointed by the prospect.
我是说  如果我真的不知怎么回去了
I mean, if I do somehow make it back there
回到了那晚  那...
to that night, then...
那意味着我没救成她
it means that I didn't save her.
我命中注定会失败
My destiny is to fail.
然后回旋镖飞过脑袋顶
And the boomerang goes flying through the cortex,
毁掉了一切  然后西斯科说
smashing everything and Cisco's all,
我的错  这怪我
"My bad. This one's on me."
听起来你们过的挺刺激的
Sounds like you had some crazy times.
是啊没错
Yeah, we have.
你准备好回归正常生活了吗
Are you ready for life to get back to normal?
你想说什么
What do you mean?
我是想我们可以离开这里
I was thinking we could leave town.
在别的地方重新开始
Start fresh somewhere.
我们的生活在这  我的工作在这
Our lives are here. My job is here.
是啊  猎杀超能力者
Yeah, hunting meta-humans.
这事没那么简单
There's more to it than that.
还非常危险
And it's dangerous.
是有些
It can be.
你看  我留在尖端科研实验室
Look, I stayed at S.T.A.R. Labs
是因为我相信威尔斯博士
because I believed in Dr. Wells.
但是自从巴里成为了闪电侠
But ever since Barry became The Flash
我们就一直在保护着城市的安全
and we've been working to keep this city safe,
我找到了新的帮助人们的方法
I found a new way to help people.
凯特  我不是生任何人的气
Look, Cait, I'm not mad at anyone.
我知道粒子加速器爆炸是场意外
Okay, I know the accelerator explosion was an accident.
但是那地方夺走了我们一年的时间
But that building took a year of our lives.
我不想再让它继续这么剥夺下去了
I don't want it to take anymore.
你们还需要点什么吗
Do you guys need anything else?
我们马上就要关门了
We're about to close up.
我不用了  宝贝
I'm good. Babe?
罗尼  趴下
Ronnie, get down.
快离开这
Get out of here.
不  我要和你一起
No, not without you.
我会跟在你后边  走
I'm right behind you-- go!
教授
Professor?
马丁
Martin?
出了什么事
What's wrong?
我不知道  我...
I don't know, I...
我感觉到恐惧
I feel terrified.
我的心跳在加快
My-- my heart is racing.
手都举起来
Hands in the air!
我想  我想罗纳德遇到麻烦了
I think-- I think Ronald is in trouble.
你怎么会知道的
How could you know that?
吉特咖啡店  他需要你的帮助
Jitters. He needs help.
快去
Go!
罗纳德·雷蒙德
Ronald Raymond.
火人本体
Burning Man himself.
不过只是一半
Half of him, anyway.
你是谁
Who are you?
韦德·艾林将军  美国陆军
General Wade Eiling, United States Army.
你想要什么
What do you want?
火风暴
Firestorm.
刺痛  对吧
Stings, doesn't it?
这东西是专门为你研发的
Had that one developed especially for you.
被动能吸引的微小碎片
Micro fragments attracted to kinetic energy.
火风暴是今晚的主要目标
Firestorm was tonight's main objective,
但抓到你  真是意外收获
but getting you-- that's just gravy.
快上车
Get in!
士兵们  战争开始了
Gentlemen, we are at war.
你得快点
You need to hurry,
巴里的伤口已经开始自愈
Barry's wounds are starting to heal
可碎片还在皮肤里
with the fragments still under his skin.
这和我那次踩了海胆的情况一样
This is just like that time I stepped on a sea urchin.
只是更糟糕
Only much worse.
别尿在我身上
Just don't pee on me.
你知道那是个谣传吧
Uh, you know that's a myth, right?
我太蠢了
I'm so stupid.
杰森·拉什  那个帮助斯泰因教授
Jason Rush, the grad student who was helping Professor Stein
研究火风暴的研究生
with his Firestorm research,
他失踪前说军队
he said that the army
把斯泰因教授所有的材料都拿走了
took all of Professor Stein's material when he disappeared.
我早该知道是艾林将军干的
I should have known it was General Eiling.
那不是你的错
Not your fault.
他仍然认为你是制造终极人类武器的关键
He still thinks you hold the keys to the ultimate human weapon,
你们两个都是
both of you.
好吧  赶紧拔完吧
Okay, let's just finish this.
我要去斯泰因家一趟
I gotta get to Stein's house.
艾林肯定会去找他
Eiling's gonna be after him too.
斯泰因没事
Stein's fine.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
他就在那
He's right there.
我认为雷蒙德先生和我
I don't think Mr. Raymond and I are as
并不像我们期望中的那样独立
distinctive as we had hoped.
我还在罗纳德体内
I'm still inside Ronald.
这话有更好的说法来表达吧
There has to be a better way to phrase that.
贝它  阿尔法  西塔  德耳塔
Beta, Alpha, Theta, Delta--
你们所有的脑电波完全同步
all your brain waves are perfectly in sync.
发生这种事的几率几乎是不可能的
The chances of that happening are next to impossible.
不可能对我们来说是司空见惯了  记得吗
Impossible's just another Tuesday for us, remember?
但这就像是《阴阳魔界》级别的东西
Yeah, but this is like some Twilight Zone level stuff,
我说这话的基础还建立在
and I say that knowing full well
我们的地下室关着一个
that we have a guy locked up in our basement
能把自己变成毒气的人之上
who can turn himself into poison gas.
等等  真的吗
Wait, really?
那好像是第三周的事了
Dude, that was, like, week three.
如果艾林像你所说的那样危险
Look, if this Eiling is as dangerous as you say,
那我得去警告克莱丽莎
then I need to warn Clarissa.
我保证能把克莱丽莎及时带出城
I promise, I can get Clarissa out of the city in time,
但是我们需要你留在这
but we need you to stay here.
教授  你得相信我们
Professor, I need you to trust us.
那好吧
Very well.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
只是这不是我所熟悉的尖端科研实验室
Yeah, it's just not the S.T.A.R. Labs I knew.
罗尼  这世界都不是你所熟悉的了
Ronnie, this isn't the world that you knew.
可不是吗
Tell me about it.
好了  我们到了
All right, here we are.
好了
Uh, all right.
你们可以暂时住在爱瑞丝以前的房间里
You guys can stay down in Iris' old room.
有点小  不过...
It's kind of small, but--
-有客人来了  -是的  但愿你没意见
- We have guests. - Yeah, we do. I hope that's okay.
请便
Mi casa.
这是罗尼
This is Ronnie.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
罗尼  那个...
Ronnie, the...
过世的未婚夫
Dead fiance.
没错
Right.
喝啤酒吗
Beer?
谢谢
Thanks.
老爸  巴里
Dad? Barry?
-爱瑞丝  你好  -你好
- Iris, hi. - Hi.
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
今天是周二
Uh, it's Tuesday.
由我来做晚饭  记得吗
I was gonna make us dinner, remember?
-对  -是
- Yep. - Yeah.
我来帮忙  给我吧
Here, I'll help. Got it.
我就知道你们会忘记
I knew you'd forget.
东西足够给所有人的了
Well, there's plenty for everyone.
凯特琳  什么风把你吹来了
Caitlin, what brings you by?
我公寓的煤气泄漏了
There's a gas leak in my apartment,
巴里说我们可以暂时住在这
so Barry said that we could stay here.
他可真贴心
Oh, that's sweet of him.
这位是谁
And, uh, who's this?
这是...
This is, uh...
她的表兄
Her cousin.
山姆
Sam.
从海滨城来看她
Visiting from Coast City.
你看起来很眼熟  山姆
You look really familiar, Sam.
是啊  我就是那种大众脸
Yeah, I-I have... one of those faces.
晚餐有什么吃的
So what's for dinner?
哈里森
Harrison.
韦德
Wade.
我有预感你会来
I had a feeling you would be wheeling by.
告诉我
Tell me.
他们还在忙着帮巴里·艾伦拔针吗
They still pulling needles out of Barry Allen's hide?
我想你的小甜心闪电侠并不希望
I guess your sweet little Flash didn't want
桑苏西中卫死时看到的只是一副面具
Sergeant Sans Soucie to die looking into a mask.
对不起  我没看到他
I'm sorry. I didn't see him.
我不知道火风暴的原理
I don't know how Firestorm works.
也许你不知道他们的原理
Well, you may not know the how,
但你知道那是谁
but you know the who.
他们俩
Both of them.
多亏你  哈里森
Thanks to you,
我们看见了新时代的曙光
it's the dawn of a new age, Harrison.
冷战  恐怖袭击
Cold War, the war on terror.
当这两个疯子联合在一起的时候
We'll seem like cave men fighting with sticks
我们就好像山顶洞人拿着棍子在战斗
once those two freaks bind together.
等你做好正确的决定
Well, you know where to find me
你知道上哪找我
when you've come to the right decision.
我知道你会的
And I know you will.
毕竟  你是我认识的最聪明的人
After all, you're the smartest guy I know.
巴仔
Bar?
我是不是不该给你看那些
Should I have not shown you?
不  那是我该知道的
No, I had to know.
我们经历过太多了
We have been through so much.
你经历太多了  你这一生
You have, all your life.
你变得这么坚强
And you've been so strong.
但我还是你的监护人
But I am still your guardian,
我的职责就是守护你
and it's my job to guard you,
不只是身体上的  还有心灵上的
not just physically, but from heartache.
我忍不住觉得
I can't help but feeling like
我刚给了你一个新包袱
I just handed you a brand new burden.
对  但这是我们的包袱  对吧
Yeah. But it's our burden, right?
没错
Yeah. Yeah.
我能问你个问题吗
Hey, can I ask you something?
你怎么知道房里的血迹是我的
How did you know that the blood in the house belonged to me?
你们一定有专门检验过
You would have had to have tested it specifically.
西斯科比照检验了所有在
Cisco tested it against everyone
尖端科研实验室工作的人
who worked at S.T.A.R. labs.
你想知道这是不是威尔斯的血迹
You wanted to know if it belonged to Wells?
乔
Joe.
威尔斯博士跟我妈妈的死毫无关系
Dr. Wells had nothing to do with my mom's murder.
你现在信了吗
You believe that now?
信了
Yeah.
信了  我信
Yeah, yeah--I do.
干杯
Cheers.
好酒
Delicious.
这些设备很让人惊艳
This is quite an impressive facility.
曾经是
Well, it was.
现在恐怕只是一个空壳了
Now it's just a shell, I'm afraid.
眼睁睁看着毕生精力毁于一旦
Must have been devastating, seeing your life's work
一定让你痛彻心扉
fall to pieces before your eyes.
确实是  而且
It was and yet,
也是同一瞬间
it was the exact same moment
你毕生的研究有了成果
your life's work came to fruition.
我毕生的研究
My life's work?
如果在之前的十四个月
If living the last 14 months
作为结合体超能力者让我领悟到什么
as a conjoined meta-human has taught me anything,
那就是我毕生的职责
it's that my life's work
应该是做一个最佳丈夫
should have been being the best husband I could to my wife.
你没事吧  马丁
Are you all right, Martin?
不好意思  我只是...
I apologize, it's just...
我有点头昏
I feel a little light-headed.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
我...  我没事
Yeah, I'm--I'm fine.
就是一瞬间觉得有点晕眩
Just got a little dizzy for a second.
你想要火风暴的秘密
You want the secret to Firestorm.
他就有
He has it.
看到了吧  哈里森  我们能好好合作的
See, Harrison? We do work well together.
你说你认识一些尖端科研实验室
You said you knew some of the leftover scientists
剩下的科学家
at the S.T.A.R. lab.
那凯特琳·斯诺博士呢  你认识吗
What about a Caitlin Snow, M.D. You know her?
认识  怎么了
Yeah, I know her, why?
之前在一家咖啡店发生了起事故
There was an incident at a local coffee shop.
当时她在那
She was there.
那是吉特咖啡店  我曾经在那工作
That's Jitters. I used to work there.
你有不会做的事吗
Is there anything you can't do?
目击者发誓他们看到士兵们射击这个地方
Witnesses swear they saw soldiers shooting the place up,
所以我联系了军方的
so I contacted the Army's
媒体公关部询问
media relations division and asked,
"是否允许士兵在美国领土上进行此种行动"
"Are soldiers permitted to operate like that on U.S. Soil?"
你知道他们怎么说吗
You know what they told me?
真奇怪  上次我见凯特琳的时候
That's weird, Caitlin didn't mention anything
她什么都没有说
the last time I saw her.
是吗
Really?
那是何时何地
When and where was that?
我说
Yeah, I mean,
我肯定这背后是有原因的
I'm sure there's an explanation for all of this.
他没伤害你吗
He didn't hurt you?
巴里  我说了  受伤的只有我的自尊
Barry, I told you-- only my pride is hurt.
很遗憾  面对荷枪实弹的士兵
Unfortunately, I'm not in the position
我真的无能为力
to take on armed soldiers.
你觉得艾林把斯泰因教授带去哪了
Where do you think Eiling took Professor Stein?
我估计在某个机密的军事研究所里
I imagine some off-the-books military research facility.
我们必须救他回来
We have to get him back.
别冲动  艾林已然展示过了
Easy--Eiling has already demonstrated
他有武器可以挟制闪电侠  或更糟
he has the weaponry to disable The Flash, or worse.
那我们也不能让他把斯泰因变成武器吧
Well, we can't let him turn Stein into a weapon.
我们怎么才能找到他
How do we find him?
干嘛
What?
无反常脑部活动
No abnormal brain activity.
生命体征稳定
All vitals steady.
你们真认为罗尼能感知到
You really think Ronnie can somehow feel
他们关押斯泰因的地点吗
where they're keeping Stein?
当士兵带走斯泰因时  罗尼感到一阵晕眩
Ronnie got dizzy when the soldiers grabbed Stein,
而斯泰恩也变得和罗尼一样喜欢披萨
and Stein developed Ronnie's obsession with pizza.
我现在什么也感知不到
I don't feel anything right now.
再加把劲
Just keep trying.
不管是什么原因  这不是想来就来的
Whatever this is, it doesn't have an on and off switch.
估计很可能只是某种剩余连接
It's possible it's just some kind of residual connection.
你们合体期间留下的暂时连接
A temporary link to your time together.
等等  我有感觉了
Wait. I feel something.
我很冷
I'm--I'm cold.
这里冷死了
It's freezing in here!
很抱歉  很快就会暖和起来了
My apologies. It should warm up pretty quick.
我知道你想要什么
I know what you want.
但我的研究并不是用来制造武器的
But my research was never intended to be used as a weapon.
我20岁就入伍了  教授
I joined the military when I was 20 years old, Professor.
我父亲让我相信我们面临的最大威胁
My father had me convinced that our greatest threat
就是苏联
was the Soviets.
我们最怕的是核战争
Our greatest fear--nuclear war.
然后出现了恐怖主义
Then came terrorism
和埃博拉病毒
and Ebola.
而现在  到了火风暴的时代
And now, it's the age of Firestorm.
通过你的项目增强的士兵  教授
Soldiers enhanced by your project, Professor.
可以赤手空拳
Soldiers who can generate
发射能量波的士兵
energy blasts with their bare hands.
可以飞天的士兵
Soldiers who can fly.
我宁愿死  也不想看到我毕生心血
I would gladly die before I see my life's work
被扭曲至此
perverted in this way.
很好  因为你死定了  教授
Good. Because you will die, Professor.
至于何时发生  就取决于你了
How soon I let that happen, though, is entirely up to you.
这是干什么
What's going on?
上次用这刑时  还是对一个大猩猩
Last time I did this was to a gorilla.
没事的  老兄  有我们在呢
You're okay, man, we got you.
他这是怎么了
What's happening to him?
他没事
Nothing's happening to him.
是斯泰因有事  罗尼感知到了他的疼痛
It's happening to Stein, and Ronnie is feeling his pain.
我想错了
I was wrong.
他们之间的连结不是暂时的
The connection's not temporary.
反而越来越强了
It's only getting stronger.
坚持住
Just try and hold on.
水  水
Water. Water.
哎呀  哎呀
My, my, my, my, my, my.
没想到一个教书的还挺能忍
You show remarkable grit for a teacher.
真让我开了眼了
I am impressed.
你还是先喘口气吧
Why don't we let you catch your breath?
顺带想想你还要忍多久
Think about how much more of this you want to endure.
罗尼  住手
Ronnie, no!
等等  凯特
Wait, Cait, wait.
他在用玻璃片划自己
He's cutting himself.
我看见了  让他划
I know. Let him.
在哪儿
是罗纳德
Ronald.
27号军事研究所
有回应吗
Anything?
没  什么都没  就是...很凉
Nothing. Nothing, just...just cold.
感觉是金属表面  一下一下的
Like a metal surface. Pressure on and on and off.
嗒  嗒  嗒
Tap, tap. Tap.
嗒  嗒
Tap. Tap.
嗒  嗒  嗒
Tap, tap, tap.
是摩尔斯电码
Morse code.
交给我了
I got this.
还是一样的  嗒  嗒
Same thing again. Tap, tap.
嗒
Tap.
嗒  嗒  嗒
Tap, tap, tap.
-是27 -那是什么意思
- 27. - What does it mean?
军事基地  通常都有数字代码  像51区
Army bases--they sometimes go by numbers, like Area 51.
是27号研究所  大概三百英里远
Facility 27, about 300 miles away.
于1961年关闭的
It was shut down in 1961.
斯泰因一定被关在那儿
Well, that's where they're keeping Stein.
估计外星人也关在那里
Bet you that's where they're keeping aliens too.
-我和你一起去  -不  你不能去
- I'm coming with you. - No, you're not.
你不能去
You can't.
我跟斯泰因相连着  我必须去
I'm connected to Stein. I have to go.
但你有没有想过你跟他的联系
But did you ever stop to think why your connection
为什么越来越强了
to him is growing stronger by the minute?
可能你们俩又要结合到一起了
Maybe you're being drawn back together.
或许你们俩靠近的话就会又融为一体了
Maybe your proximity will cause you to re-merge into one.
如果他被杀死了  我会怎么样
And what happens to me if he gets killed?
凯特  巴里说得对
Cait, Barry was right.
世界已经变了
The world is different now.
我以为我们可以离开这
Look, I--I thought we could get away,
一起开始新生活  正常的生活
start a new life, a normal life, together.
但是对于我们来说没有什么正常的生活
But there is no normal life for us.
你总是会冒着生命危险去帮助别人
You will always risk your life to try and help people,
而我也总会为了你
and I will always be the guy that
闯进管道监狱
runs into that Pipeline for you.
量子连接器
The Quantum Splicer.
它把你们分开过一次
It was used to separate you once.
或许能让你们不再融为一体
Maybe it could be of use to keep you you.
谢了
Thanks.
-好了  出发  -等等
- Okay, let's go. - Wait.
你们三个  一定要安全回来
Come back. All three of you.
出发
Let's go.
禁区
这地方真是一点也不恐怖啊
This place definitely doesn't look too shady.
斯泰因在里面
Stein's inside.
我能感觉到我们连接变强了
I can feel our connection growing stronger,
就像他在拽我一样
like he's pulling me.
我就担心这个  火风暴矩阵
It's as I feared-- the Firestorm Matrix
会在接近时再次发生融合
is building toward a proximity reemergence.
就像所有物质一样  它想要成为一个整体
Like all matter, it yearns to be whole.
如果你们俩融为一体
If you do merge...
我们可能无法再将你们分开了
we might not be able to separate you again.
我们已经将目标
We've been able to isolate the Firestorm Matrix
细胞中的火风暴矩阵隔离了
inside the subject's cellular structure.
很好
Excellent.
斯泰因教授
Professor Stein,
恐怕你的想法大错特错了
I'm afraid you have made a terrible assumption...
我不需要你活着
that I need you alive.
艾林用枪指着斯泰因的头
Eiling has a gun to Stein's head.
他要开枪了
He's about to pull the trigger.
他来这了
He's here.
我从没想过会很高兴见到你
I never thought I'd be happy to see you.
-是的  我也是  -我们赶紧离开这吧
- Yeah, likewise. - Let's get out of here.
快跑
Run!
好吧  走  快走
Okay, come on, come on.
巴里  你衣服上的PH值好像很不正常
Barry, I'm picking up some serious PH numbers on your suit.
他们用化学物质击中了我
They hit me with some kind of chemical.
是一种武器化的磷
It's a weaponized phosphorous.
水或者泡沫都浇不灭
Water or foam won't extinguish it.
但它在真空里无法燃烧
But you can't burn in a vacuum,
所以你要造一个真空环境
so you need to create one.
跑  巴里  跑
Run, Barry. Run!
-我们要再次融合  -罗尼  不要
- We need to merge again. - Ronnie, no!
凯特  不融合的话我们会死的
Cait, we're dead if we don't.
听我说
Listen to me.
上次你们结合的时候  你们都在抗拒
The last time you two combined, you both fought it.
这次不要了
This time, don't.
接受这个改变  接受这个平衡
Accept the change, accept the balance.
接受彼此
Accept each other.
让我们再上战场吧  亲爱的朋友
Once more unto the breach, dear friend.
凯特
Cait...
无论发生什么  要记住我永远爱你
whatever happens, just remember I'll always love you.
你能听见我吗  罗纳德
Can you hear me, Ronald?
教授
Professor?
看来我们这次融合得没问题
It appears we merged properly on this attempt.
威尔斯让我们接受彼此是对的
Wells was right about balance and accepting.
你后面
Behind you!
罗尼  他们来了更多的人
Ronald, there's more of them.
艾林  现在一切都结束了
Eiling, this ends now.
是的  没错
Yes, it does...
你们俩都完了
for both of you.
离子炸弹
An ion grenade.
用足够多的离子攻击你的细胞结构
Just bombarded your cellular structure with enough ions
就能使你们的矩阵不稳定
to destabilize your matrix.
雷蒙德先生  斯泰因教授
Mr. Raymond, Professor Stein,
你们都是优秀的美国人
you're both fine Americans.
国家感谢你们的牺牲
Your country thanks you for your sacrifice.
我跑了好久
That was a lot of running.
罗尼
Ronnie?
-回家吗  -是的
- Home? - Yeah.
我觉得它看上去更糟糕一些
I think it looks worse than it is.
你是罗尼还是斯泰因
Ronnie or Stein?
是我  凯特
It's me, Cait.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
好吧  是我们两个
It's both of us. Somehow.
她很可爱
She's quite lovely.
接受是一件很强大的事
Acceptance is a powerful thing.
强大到能逆转吗
Powerful enough to reverse it?
你想的话我愿意一试  雷蒙德先生
I'm game if you are, Mr. Raymond.
我们可以试试
We could try.
我想我们已经掌握到诀窍了
I think we're getting the hang of this quite nicely.
没关系
It's okay.
我明白  你得走了
I understand. You have to go.
你怎么知道的
How'd you know?
我也和你连接上了
I'm connected to you too.
你要去哪里
Where will you go?
可能去匹兹堡吧
Pittsburgh, maybe.
斯泰因教授认为他有个同事
Professor Stein has a colleague he thinks
可以帮我们更进一步了解我们的能力
can help us learn more about our abilities.
我们在这里也能帮你
We can help you here too.
艾林已经攻入了尖端科研实验室
Eiling has already breached S.T.A.R. Labs.
我们必须领先他一步...
We need to stay one step ahead of him...
为了所有人着想
for all of us.
-我会回来的  -到时我们一起吃披萨
- I'm coming back. - We'll have pizza.
祝成功  艾伦先生
Godspeed, Mr. Allen.
同祝
You too.
关于我们之前的谈话
As to our earlier conversation,
我相信第二次机会
I believe in second chances.
你也会有的
You'll get yours.
假以时日
Give it time.
准备好了吗  罗纳德
Ready, Ronald?
别再那样叫我了
Please stop calling me that.
希望不久能见到你
I'll see you soon.
爱你们
We love you.
我曾经拥有罗尼  然后失去他了
I had Ronnie, then I lost him.
然后我找到他了  但那其实不是罗尼
Then I found him again, but he wasn't actually Ronnie.
然后我找回了他  一天之后又失去了
Then I got him back but just for a day until I lost him again.
你们像整个十季中的罗斯和蕾切尔
You guys are like 10 seasons of Ross and Rachel,
《老友记》角色
不过被压缩进了一年里
but just, like, smushed into one year.
这次我没有心碎
I am not heartbroken this time.
我爱罗尼  一直都爱
I love Ronnie. I always will,
但是我心里已经没有那种巨大的伤痕了
but there's not this devastating hole inside me.
我有我的生活  好的生活
I have a life, and it's a good one.
你们好
Hey, guys.
-爱瑞丝  你好  -你好
- Iris, hi. - Hi.
你的表兄呢
Where is your cousin?
他回家了
Uh, he went home.
那是在哪里来着
Oh. Uh, where was that again?
中途岛
Uh, Midway.
我记得你以前说的是海滨城
Oh, I thought you said Coast City.
去中途岛  途径海滨城
Uh, Midway via Coast City.
他经常来来去去的
He moved around a lot.
这还真挺辛苦的
That's always really hard.
好啦  尽兴
All right, well. Enjoy.
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - See you.
你要告诉我这是什么意思吗
Am I supposed to know what that means?
意思是我打算帮你搞明白
It means that I'm gonna help you figure out
尖端科研实验室到底发生了什么
what's going on at S.T.A.R. Labs.
我想火人以前在那里工作
I think our Burning Man used to work there.
你为什么要我来这里
So why'd you bring me here?
我不知道是怎样  或是何时
I don't know how and I don't know when,
但是某一日  我将会回到十五年前的
but one day soon, I'm gonna be in this house again,
这间房子
15 years ago.
然后我会失败...
And I'm gonna fail...
除非这次我能扭转乾坤
Unless this time, I don't.
你在说什么
What are you saying?
知道我会输给了我优势
Knowing that I'm supposed to lose gives me the advantage.
这些画面告诉了我什么不该做
Those images are a lesson in what not to do.
当再次与黄衣人对决时
When I face off against the man in yellow,
我不会再犯同样的错误
I won't make the same mistake twice.
你要改变历史吗
You're gonna... change the past?
乔  我要救我妈妈
Joe... I'm gonna save my mom.
那到底是什么
What--what the hell was that?
很高兴再见到你  将军
It's good to see you again, General.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是谁
Who am I?
哈里森  你跟他们一样
Harrison... You're one of them.
是超能力者
A meta-human.
没错  我是
Yes, I am.
而且我保护我的同类
And I protect my own.
那是什么
What was that?
那是...
Now, that...
我们的老朋友
is an old friend of ours.
将军...
General...
这  声音
That...voice...
在我脑子里
It's in my head.
上帝呐
Dear God.
不是上帝  是古鲁德
Not God. Grodd.